staradvertiser.com 2019-12-25

# Privacy Policy | Oahu Publications

Oahu Publications, Incorporated and its affiliates (collectively, “Oahu Publications Inc.”, “OPI”, “we”, “us” or “our”) operate newspapers, and news, entertainment and informational websites, and other digital and online services.  This Privacy Policy applies only the information we collect through our websites, mobile applications, electronic devices, kiosks, and all other interactive services we provide, referred to collectively as the “Services”.

**What information do we collect?**

The information that we collect about you while during your use of the Services falls into three general categories:

  * **Information You Provide to Us.  Our Services may collect and store information, personal or otherwise, that you voluntarily supply by:  
**

  1.     1. interacting with our websites.  

    2. corresponding with us through email, phone, or online chat (via our social media channels).

Some examples of this type of information include demographic information that you electronically submit, such as:

  1.     1.       1.         1. when you sign up for access to certain features on the Service,  

        2. information (such as your name or e-mail address) that you electronically submit when you register for surveys, sweepstakes or contests on our websites, 
        3. information that you post as comments on the our websites, and 
        4. information contained in search requests or questions that you submit to the our websites. 

  * ****Information that is Automatically Collected.   We may collect and store information that is generated automatically as you navigate our websites. This information may be:  
  
a. technical information, including the internet protocol (IP) address used to connect to your computer to the Internet, the browser type and version you use, the type of mobile device, the mobile network used, as well as the computer operating system and platform;  
  
b. information on your visit to any of our platforms, including the full uniform resource locators (URL) to and from our platforms (including date and time), pages you viewed, and page response times. ****
  * Information that We Receive from Others. We may receive information about you from other websites we operate (as listed above). We also work with third parties such as analytics providers, advertising networks, search information providers, hosting platforms, and payment processors, and may receive information about you from them.

**How is the Information Used?**

We use the information we collect from you while you are using the Services in a variety of ways, including:

  1. Validating your identity in order to access products and features of the website.
  2. Sending you email communications in the form of newsletters or email marketing.
  3. Using the information to customize features and advertising that appear on our websites. 

In addition, we may also provide third parties with information about our visitors for a variety of reasons and purposes. For example, we may provide our advertisers with information about our visitors that will better target ads to specific types of visitors.

Therefore, OPI reserves the right to use and to disclose to third parties all of the information that we collect online about you and other visitors in any way and for any purpose, with one important exception.

We will not use the information that it collects online from you while you are using the Service, nor will we authorize third parties to use such information to mail or e-mail promotional offers directly to you unless you have specifically informed us that you would like to receive promotional offers from us and from third parties. If you choose to receive these promotional offers, then your information may be used for direct mail or e-mail marketing. You may view or update your preference to receive these promotional offers by visiting our websites.

Please also keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online — for example on message boards, comments, through e-mail, or in chat areas — that information can be seen, collected and used by others besides our Services. We cannot be responsible for any unauthorized third party use of information that you disclose online.

Please note our Services may include links to other websites, and provide access to products and services offered by third parties, whose privacy policies we do not control. When you access another website or purchase products or services or conduct other transactions through the Service, use of any information you provide is governed by the privacy policy of the operator of the site you are visiting or the provider of such products or services.

We also make some content, products and services available through our Service through cooperative relationships with third party providers, where the brands of our provider partner appear prominently on our Services. We may share with our provider partner any information you provide, or that is collected, in the course of visiting any pages that are made available in cooperation with our provider partner. In some cases, the provider partner may collect information from you directly; in which cases the privacy policy of the provider partner may apply to the provider partner’s use of your information. The privacy policy of our provider partners may differ from ours. If you have any questions regarding the privacy policy of one of our provider partners, you should contact the provider directly for more information.

Be aware that we may occasionally release information about visitors when release is appropriate to comply with law, to enforce our Terms of Service agreement, or to protect the rights, property or safety of visitors to our site, the public, or OPI.

Please also note that as our business grows, we may buy or sell various assets. In the unlikely event that OPI, some or all of our assets, is acquired by another company, information on our visitors may be among the transferred assets.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp

**How is the information shared?**

  1. We may share your personal information with our network of sites.
  2. We may share your information with selected third parties including:
    1. business partners, to fulfill any service contract, for example email newsletters, that we have entered into with you.
    2. advertisers and advertising networks that require your data in order to serve you relevant advertisements. Please note that we do not disclose any information that identifies individuals to our advertisers, but provide only aggregate data about our users (for example, you are a man, under 30).
    3. analytics and search engine providers that assist us in improving our platforms.
    4. legal requests such as a subpoena, court order, or other governmental request.

**Children’s Privacy Statement**

This children’s privacy statement explains our practices with respect to the online collection and use of personal information from children under the age of thirteen, and provides important information on your rights under federal law with respect to such information.

We do NOT knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. We screen users who wish to provide personal information in order to prevent users under the age of thirteen from providing such information. If we become aware that we have inadvertently received personally identifiable information from a user under the age of thirteen, we will delete such information from our records. If we change our practices in the future, we will obtain prior, verifiable parental consent before collecting any personally identifiable information from children under the age of thirteen.

Because we do not collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of thirteen, we also do NOT knowingly distribute such information to third parties.

We do NOT knowingly allow children under the age of thirteen to publicly post or otherwise distribute personally identifiable contact information.

Because we do not collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of thirteen, we do NOT condition the participation in online activities of a child under thirteen on providing personally identifiable information.  
  
**Cookies Policy and Other Technologies**  

To enhance your experience on our websites, we use a standard feature found in browser software called a “cookie.”  Cookies are small files that your web browser places on your hard drive for record-keeping purposes. By showing how and when visitors use our websites, cookies help us track user trends and patterns. They also prevent you from having to re-enter your preferences on certain areas of our websites where you have entered preference information before.   
  
Our Services also use web beacons (also known as “single-pixel GIFs”) to access cookies and to count users who visit our sites or open the HTML-formatted email messages associated with our Services.   
  
Another example of information that we automatically collect as you navigate our websites is information about your computer’s connection to the Internet. This information allows us, among other things, to improve the delivery of our Web pages to you and to measure traffic on our sites.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

OPI reserves the right to update this Privacy Policy at any time to reflect changes in the law, our methods of data collection, and features in the services we provide. Your continued use of these services will mean you accept those changes.

**How to Contact Us?**

  1. Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to: [webmaster@staradvertiser.com](mailto:webmaster@staradvertiser.com)
  2. Contact Office:   
Oahu Publications, Inc.  
500 Ala Moana Blvd, Suite 7-210  
Honolulu, HI 96813
